MR. KOOL HAVIS

498 Williamson St SE, Marietta, GA 30060 (919) 395-7858 • havisk@illinoisalumni.org

TECHNICAL PROJECT MANAGER/ ENGINEER/ CONSULTANT

Innovative and experienced technical project manager/consultant with a record of developing and supporting successful solutions incorporating a wide range of applications and technologies. Recognized and tasked by executive leadership to improve organizational effectiveness and efficiency through the proper implementation of development principles. Exemplary track record in leading teams in strategic project initiatives and guiding companies through consultive process implementation techniques. Innovative and forward-thinking leader utilizing progressive methods for team building and knowledge transfer in various industries. Diverse understanding of planning and directing various highly complex projects and effectively reducing company costs through innovative utilization of resources.

CORE COMPETENCIES

Problem Identification • Strategic and Tactical Planning • Budget Control • Contract Negotiation
Project Management • Relationship Management • Training • Data Analysis • Cost Reduction
Emergent Technologies • Design Review • Product Development • Technology Integration • Help Desk•
Hardware/Software Installation and Configuration • Advanced CRM Competency – Microsoft Dynamics CRM
Customization • UX/UI Design and Development • Web Application and Site Development

CERTIFICATIONS/TECHNICAL SKILLS

Certifications/Professional Development: Microsoft Dynamics CRM 2011 & 2013 Customizations and

Configurations-Certified

Microsoft Dynamics CRM 2013 Applications - **Certified**Managing Microsoft Dynamics Implementations - **Certified**Certified Associate Project Management - Certification Track

Security+ - Certified

Hardware: Cisco series routers/switches such as: 2600, 2800,

2900, 3500, 3700, 7200, 7600.

Software/Protocol: Cisco IOS, ARP, NAT, LERG, VOIP, SIP, MGCP, DNS, POP3, FTP,

TCP/IP, UDP, SMTP, SNMP, ICMP, DHCP, EIGRP, IGRP, BGP,

OSPF, ATM.

Technical Skills: Languages: SQL, JavaScript, AngularJS, BackboneJS

JQuery, ReactJS, UnderScoreJS Python, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Git

Databases:Oracle, SQL Server and MS AccessOS Platforms:Mac, Microsoft Windows XP - 10, UNIXMethodologies:Agile, Waterfall, Iterative and Rational

Unified Process, Agile-Scrum

Others: SQL Analyzer, Microsoft Project 2010,

Sure Step, Unity3d



MR. KOOL HAVIS PAGE 2

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

The Iron Yard

Front-End Engineer, Atlanta, GA

2015 to Present

A tweleve week immersive coding mentorship

- Build web apps and websites leveraging HTML5 and JavaScript (Plain, Angular, JQuery, React)
- Style using CSS3, SASS, Foundation
- Collaborate with others on projects
- Use Git for version control
- Work with RESTful web services
- Assure all user inputs are validated before submitting to back-end

American College Of Rheumatology, Atlanta, GA

2015 to 2015

MS Dynamics CRM Specialist

- Provide advice on CRM features and the use of the system.
- Subject matter expert during requirement gathering sessions
- Configure CRM to meet client's requirements
- Customize CRM as client's needs change.
- Review JavaScript and remove code no longer needed
- Conduct root cause analysis for systems issues..
- Resolve CRM application errors and provide a solution to the issues in a cost-effective, efficient, and timely manner.

Affiliated Resource Group Inc., Dublin OH

MS Dynamics CRM Implementation Consultant

2013 to 2014

- Handled all aspects of client communication
- Utilized an automated issue tracking system to manage large complex projects
- Addressed prioritization and issue resolution
- Utilized a formal Change Management process to manage change approval and scope creep
- Assured project completion on time within budget
- Completed Business Requirement definition sessions with clients
- Converted Business Requirement into Functional requirements
- Tailored the Microsoft Dynamics System in a "shoulder to shoulder mode" with the client demonstrating the system capabilities
- Developed client specific training plans
- Developed training materials tailored to the client's CRM system configuration
- Built CRM Lab exercises that mirrored the training materials and reinforced knowledge

Aderant, Atlanta, GA

MS Dynamics CRM Implementation Consultant

2012 to 2013

- Gathered and documented clients business and technical requirements.
- Coordinated technical resources for installations, migrations, data cleansing, integrations, and other custom development
- Executed all project management activities including status meetings, status reports, issue tracking, budget management, and risk management.
- Managed to client satisfaction and application/solution quality goals.
- Contributed to the company's implementation methodology by creating tools and templates

MR. KOOL HAVIS PAGE 3

• Researched and provid training materials for CRM Team.

TargetIT, Norcross, GA

2011 to 2012

MS Dynamics CRM Consultant

- Designed and implemented strategies for creation of Business Units and Security Roles.
- Created and configured Microsoft Dynamics CRM Users and Teams.
- Created and configured fields for custom and system entities. Design, create and configure relationships between entities.
- Created and configured Views, Charts and Forms for system and custom entities.
- Implemented Field Security in Microsoft Dynamics CRM.
- Designed, created and configured Solutions in Microsoft Dynamics CRM; implementing both managed and unmanaged Solutions.

NCR, Peachtree City, GA

2010 to 2011

Helpdesk Support

- Managed calls and utilized the Remedy ticketing system to monitor and follow up on open cases.
- Performed troubleshooting on hardware and software, performing root cause analysis and ordering replacement parts.
- Followed standardized departmental policy and procedures for diagnostic, troubleshooting, and problem solving completing special projects as assigned.
- Met corporate and departmental objectives effectively, anticipating problems and recognizing the when to deviate from standard practices.

US Air National Guard, Marietta, GA **Cyber Transport Specialist**

2008 to 2014

- Provide mission critical voice, data, and video services, installing systems/circuits/IP-based, and managing infrastructure devices and systems using the latest approved software tools.
- Remove and replace assemblies and subassemblies to optimally sustain voice, data, and video networks, effectively managing projects and isolating malfunctions using diagnostic software, technical data, block diagrams, voltage and waveform measurements.
- Maintain network and circuit databases, records, and forms, coordinating requests for service orders, reviewing and recommending changes to communications-computer systems installations records (CSIR).
- Update and verify entries on system, facility, maintenance, and inspection records. Initiate, track, and maintain shipping, receiving, supply, and equipment documents.
- Conduct periodic inspections of systems installations and repair activities, interpreting
 inspection reports and implementing corrective actions, document inspection,
 and maintenance actions.
- Ensure equipment and components to meet installation practice technical order and are accepted for commercial installation specifications.
- Serve as advisor at meetings for facility design, military construction programs and minor construction planning, evaluating base comprehensive plan and civil engineering projects.

Comcast, Atlanta, GA

2005 to 2008

Quality Assurance Analyst

- Prepared test cases by going through the Design documents and Functional Requirements, performed extensive Manual Testing and System Testing of the application, and executed Manual Test Cases.
- Created the test data for regression testing, reviewing initial BRD, and documenting the overall requirements.

MR. KOOL HAVIS PAGE 4

 Developed the Use Case documents and Test Plans for various New Products, serving integral role in Development End testing and PLI testing. Conducted FACETS testing and collaborated with developers to close the defects.

Blue Cross Blue Shield, Atlanta, GA **Quality Assurance Analyst**

2003 to 2005

- Performed extensive Manual and Black Box Testing of the application, documenting Test Cases for Integration, User Acceptance testing, and Functional testing.
- Tested back-end using SQL statements for data manipulation and created weekly status reports showing the progress of Manual Testing effort.
- Developed expertise in PeopleSoft Financials Applications testing (BI,AR, AP,GL Purchase, Billing) modules.

Cingular Wireless, Atlanta, GA **Quality Assurance Consultant**

2001 to 2003

- Developed and executed test plans, prepared work schedules, resourced planning and performed reporting. Documented Test Plan and Test Cases, implementing Regression testing, Functionality, and Black box Testing using Win Runner.
- Performed End-to-End testing and developed traceability matrix to trace requirements during the QA testing phase and -maintained the requirements traceability matrix.
- Performed database testing using SQL queries within Oracle.
- Executing test cases and identified mismatches.
- Developed documentation for User Acceptance Testing and trained the users about the system.
- Automated baseline scripts generated using Win Runner to perform Regression testing for different application builds.

EDUCATION

Master of Information Technology, Project Management American InterContinental University Master of Science, Engineering Conservatory Tempe, AZ Bachelor of Science, Biochemistry University of Illinois Urbana-Champaign, IL

SECURITY CLEARANCE: Active